Guide to the Harris Masterson I papers,1860-1942, bulk 1880-1920 MS 468
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series IV: Legal / Court Cases, 1871-1920 (Boxes 103-131)
  - Somerville matter, 1895 (Box 128, Folder 10)
  - Diana Spanier Baltimore property, 1900-1901 (Box 128, Folder 11)
  - E. Strauss, 1917-1918 (Box 128, Folder 12)
  - Perry Sweeney notes, 1908-1910 (Box 128, Folder 13)
  - J.A. Swindler, 1913-1919 (Box 128, Folder 14)
  - J.H. Tankersley, 1890s (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Isaac Taylor, 1901- (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Taylor land, 1901 (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - Taylor title papers (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - [State of] Texas v. Goldman, 1908 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Texas Trust Co. v. Campbell (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - Trench matter, 1901-1903 (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - W.B. Turner, 1899, 1901 (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - J.C. Underwood paving contracts, 1912-1915 (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - J.C. Underwood paving contracts, 1912-1915 (Box 129, Folder 10)
  - Ruth Carvens Ward estate, 1911, 1913 (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Wheaton vs. Universal Tire Rubber Co., 1919 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - W.R. Wilbur, 1906-1907, 1910 (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - Ella Wilson, 1880s-1890s (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - H.S.H. Wilson, 1905-1910 (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - John P. Withers, 1912-1916 (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - John P. Withers, 1912-1916 (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - Galveston Co. JP #!: Lewy vs. Lacour, 1904 (Box 131, Folder 1)
  - Galveston CCL: State vs. Beasley, 1915 (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - Cameron Co. Court: Wellborne vs. Browne, 1918 (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - Jefferson Co. JP: Masterson vs. Morgan,1901 (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - Brazoria Co. Court: Elzy Hamson estate, 1871, 1886 (Box 131, Folder 5)
  - Brazoria Co. Court: Preston McBeth, 1890s-1900 (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - Southern District of TX: Allen vs. Parmalee, c. 1902-1911 (Box 131, Folder 7)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, 4th Circuit: Pineland Club vs. R. Sanders, 1913-1915 (Box 131, Folder 8)
- Series V: Legal Correspondence / Court Documents, 1893-1917 (Boxes 132-189)
  Arranged in order beginning with County and District Court Records, then by County Court, and lastly by District Court. Within each grouping, records are arranged alphabetically by case name, and include deeds, agreements, promissory notes, and more.
  - County Clerk files, 1904-1914 (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - County Clerk files (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Court of Civil Appeals, 1905-1913 (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - Clerk vs. Court, County Judge, Ft. Bend Co. (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - First National Bank of Waco, 1914-1916 (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - District Court documents (unsorted) (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - District Court of Brazoria documents (unsorted) (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - District Court of Brazoria documents (unsorted) (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - District Court of Brazoria documents (unsorted) (Box 134, Folder 7)
  - District Clerk files (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Release of Deeds of Trust and Vendor's Lien notes (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - Transfer of Vendors' Lien notes (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Transfer of Vendor's Lien notes: Texas Town Lot Improvement Co. and Masterson Irrigation Co., 1911-1912 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Reports on abstracts and titles to properties, c. 1908-1913 (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Brazoria District Court: Rowan v. Rowan, Magee v. Mayes, Angier v. Masterson, State v. Lovett (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Brazoria District Court: Moller v. South Texas Dev. Co., Masterson v. McBride, Smith v. South Texas Dev. Co. (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - Brazoria District Court: Swihart v. Gardiner, Edwards v. Rowan (Box 136, Folder 7)
  - Brazoria District Court litigations (Box 136, Folder 8)
  - Brazoria District Court: Doran v. Stoddard, Bringham v. Warner, Brazoria Co. v. Stevens, Masterson v. Stevens, Masterson Irrigation Co. v. Owen (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Brazoria District Court: Kelly v. Masterson, Granbury v. Stockwell, Owen v. Tyson, Masterson v. Wilson, Williams v. Brown (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Brazoria District Court: Mihard v. Brown, Masterson v. Hull, Boykin v. Fulbright, Wheelwright v. Holland, Craig, v. Higgins (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Brazoria District Court: Owen v. Tyson, Stevens v. Disney, South Texas Dev. Co. v. Masterson, Masterson v. Higgins, Woulfer v. Coumpton, Slataper v. Masterson (Box 137, Folder 4)
  - Brazoria District Court: Barrow v. Scottish American Mtg. Co., Conlin v. Conlin, Masterson v. Elkins, Masterson v. Lacy, Masterson v. Bell, Masterson v. Classen (Box 137, Folder 5)
  - Brazoria District Court: State of Texas v. H. Masterson, et al (Box 137, Folder 6)
  - Brazoria District Court: numbered cases (Box 137, Folder 7)
  - Debts: Conway, Masterson, Marek, Leigh, O'Neil (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Deeds of Trust and notes (various) (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Abstracts of Title: Baker and Chapman additions, Houston (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Legal papers (various) (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - Legal papers (various) (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - Deeds of Trust, promissory notes, releases of deeds of trust (Box 138, Folder 6)
  - Compiled warranty deeds (Box 138, Folder 7)
  - Abstracts (Box 138, Folder 8)
  - Notes on title of Mariah Ximines league (Box 138, Folder 9)
  - Contract between W.J. Taylor and Masterson, 1903 (Box 138, Folder 10)
  - Agreement conveying to H. Masterson interest in settlement of title to mineral rights with Munson, Williams Munson, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - Receipt to John T. Boyle for earnest money re: purchase of property from H. Masterson, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 2)
  - Deeds conveying parcels of land to H. Masterson in settlement of Estate of J.B. Brockman, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 3)
  - Release of deed of trust by H. Masterson to John H. Crooker W.A. Saunders, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 4)
  - Release of deed of trust by H. Masterson to J.B. Brockman, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 5)
  - Release of vendor's lien by H. Masterson on property of J.B. Brockman, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 6)
  - Lease of grazing land to Louis McKensen by H. Masterson Henry Fox, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 7)
  - Agreement between H. Masterson and I. Onishi for repayment of funds advanced against rice crop, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 8)
  - Lease agreement between Masterson Irrigation Co. and E.R. Becker, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 9)
  - Power of Attorney of H. Masterson authorizing N.T. Masterson to conduct business during absence from state, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 10)
  - Release of vendor's lien on property by H. Masterson to Thomas P. Converse, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 11)
  - Substitution of Elliott Cage as trustee in case against J.P. Withers, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 12)
  - Conveyance of barber shop fixtures from Herman Fleig to Hart Wartell, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 13)
  - Agreement between Mary W. Roper and H. Masterson re: exchange of 1/3 interest in property for clearing title, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 14)
  - Powers of Attorney authoring H. Masterson and Marie Rene Perry to act on behalf of Perry heirs to recover Perry-owned land, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 15)
  - Agreement between J.K. Ayres and H. Masterson re: sale of interest in lawsuits in exchange for legal services, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 16)
  - Affidavit of D.E. Cole re: death of horse struck by lightning, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 17)
  - Chattel mortgages from Frank Hawkins to H. Masterson, 1916-17 (Box 139, Folder 18)
  - Bill of sale of cattle to H. Masterson as mortgage for Patterson Moneyhon, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 19)
  - Contract conveying interest in land from Rosina Ludtke to H. Masterson, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 20)
  - Affidavit of W.T. Williams re: Damon heirs, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 21)
  - Agreement between H. Masterson and J.L. Hudson re: conveyance of land to guarantee debt,1917 (Box 139, Folder 22)
  - Lease of land for grazing from H. Masterson to Tresler, et al, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 23)
  - Statement of F.E. Pye re: deeds and payment of debt to J.W. Towler, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 24)
  - Notice of auction to pay notes of J.T. James F.R. Harris by H. Masterson, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 25)
  - Affidavit of ownership of bonds of the Louisiana Land Pecan Co. sold to H. Masterson, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 26)
  - Incomplete grazing lease agreement between O.P. Woodbuin and H. Masterson, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 27)
  - Affidavit of J.F. James P.R. Harris re: agreement for purchase of car from H. Masterson, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 28)
  - Agreement between John Powell H. Masterson re: debt owed Masterson, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 29)
  - Conveyance of cows to H. Masterson by Mrs. M.C. Keyworth as motgage to guarantee indebtedness, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 30)
  - Earnest receipt of Sam Realty Co. to Edward Koch, 1919 (Box 139, Folder 31)
  - Abstract of title to property in Hyde Park Main Addition, Houston, 1923 (Box 139, Folder 32)
  - Field notes of survey of John Broch League (Box 139, Folder 33)
  - List of apparent owners, Robert Cameron Survey (Box 139, Folder 34)
  - Receipt, Harris Co. Bank Trust Co. to H. Masterson for settle- ment owed by Wiess estate (Box 139, Folder 35)
  - Map and price list of lots in Avondale (Box 139, Folder 36)
  - Incomplete deed of Ethel Levi Smith of land in John Merry League (Box 139, Folder 37)
  - Bond agreement on contract of V.H. Brown to H. Masterson (Box 139, Folder 38)
  - Abstract of block boundaries in Flournoy Hunt Survey (Box 139, Folder 39)
  - Contract between D.F. Rowe and A.L. Kulp for release of land and lien to Kulp and subsequent conveyance to Susan Green (Box 139, Folder 40)
  - Property listing of Nancy T. Bringhurst (Box 139, Folder 41)
  - Price list of lots in Belt Junction City suburb of Houston (Box 139, Folder 42)
  - Henderson Co.: Vendor's lien and incomplete warranty deed of H. Masterson to T.M. Mathews, Jr., 1915 (Box 139, Folder 43)
  - Henderson Co.: Release of vendor's lien by H. Masterson to T.M. Mathews, Jr. 1917 (Box 139, Folder 44)
  - Release of vendor's lien by H. Masterson to Jerry Martin and Richardson Watkins, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 45)
  - Hidalgo Co.: Release of property from Deed of Trust to T.E. Cowart by H. Masterson in exchange for other security, 1915 (Box 139, Folder 46)
  - Jasper Co.: Corresp. and deeds of trust in purchase of land by H. Masterson from R.F. Seastrunk, 1918 (Box 139, Folder 47)
  - Jefferson Co: Deed of Joseph Nancy Hutcheson to Clark Beach, 1841 (Box 139, Folder 48)
  - Jefferson Co.: Sheriff's deed of sale to B.T. Masterson to satisfy judgment on H. Masterson to B. Turner, 1901 (Box 139, Folder 49)
  - Jefferson Co.: Transfer from Sarah Jet et al to Hardin Runnels, 1906 (Box 139, Folder 50)
  - Jefferson Co.: Agreement re: trust to protect Temple Lumber Co. against loss in litigation against J.H. Broocks F. Sievert, 1912 (Box 139, Folder 51)
  - Jefferson Hardin Cos.: Deed of Trust and notes with vendor's lien of H.M. Godsey to N.T. Masterson, 1915 (Box 139, Folder 52)
  - Jefferson Co.: Abstract of land granted to Stephen Eaton by state of Coahuila, 1902 (Box 139, Folder 53)
  - Johnson Co.: Plea order of note in Irvin v. Tryon, 1905 Liberty Co. (Box 139, Folder 54)
  - Liberty Co.: Copies of deeds conveying Lewis Latham grant, 1838-1871 (Box 139, Folder 55)
  - Liberty Co.: Warranty deed of Joe Murphy et al by J.A. Tackenberry to H. Masterson, 1902 (Box 139, Folder 56)
  - Liberty Co.: Memoranda of title of Julia Ann Malley league, 1903 (Box 139, Folder 57)
  - Liberty Co.: Index to abstract for partial Samuel Strong league, 1904 (Box 139, Folder 58)
  - Liberty Co.: Copy of original patent of lant to M.A. Hardin by Governor Wood and abstracts to part of survey, 1904 (Box 139, Folder 59)
  - Liberty Co.: Deeds conveying interest in estates of Nancy Joseph Dunman to A. Goldmann, 1905 (Box 139, Folder 60)
  - Liberty Co.: Title report to various survey subdivisions of most western Liberty Town league, 1907 (Box 139, Folder 61)
  - Liberty Co.: Memorandum of title to Knight Survey (Box 139, Folder 62)
  - Liberty Co.: Contract of sale of property to O'Brien Stevens by heirs of W.H. Brown, 1913 (Box 139, Folder 63)
  - Liberty Co.: Option to purchase timber on property extended to W.A. Smith by H. Masterson, et al, 1914 (Box 139, Folder 64)
  - Liberty Co.: Receipt to W.A. Smith for notes held against W.T. Daniel, 1914 (Box 139, Folder 65)
  - Liberty Co.: Extension of notes of C.T. Edna Stevens by H. Masterson, 1915 (Box 139, Folder 66)
  - Liberty Co.: Memorandum of sale of land to F.W. Hill by H. Masterson, 1916 (Box 139, Folder 67)
  - Austin Co.: Release from Deed of Trust and lien by Elliott Cage H. Masterson to Marion F. Ward, 1914 (Box 140, Folder 1)
  - Bexar Co.: Warranty deed of J.M. Brambelord to J.B. Mock, 1896 (Box 140, Folder 2)
  - Bexar Co.: Agreement between F. Crane State Bank Trust Co. of San Antonio re: assignment of railroad bonds, 1910 (Box 140, Folder 3)
  - Bexar Co.: Agreement recognizing superiority of liens of H. Masterson over T.A. Franker, 1914 (Box 140, Folder 4)
  - Bexar Co.: Deeds of trust and notes of Hot Well Dev. Co. I.M. Putnam to N.T. Masterson for use of H. Masterson, 1914 (Box 140, Folder 5)
  - Bexar Co.: Release of vendor's lien of H. Masterson to Baileys, 1915 (Box 140, Folder 6)
  - Bexar Co.: Promissory note and deed of trust to N.T. Masterson for First Mortgage Trust Co. of San Antonio, 1915 (Box 140, Folder 7)
  - Bexar Co.: Blanco Llano Cos.: Warranty deed of Edward McDowell to H. Masterson for portion of land, 1878 (Box 140, Folder 8)
  - Brazoria Co.: Acknowledgments re: conveyance of land in Thomas Alsbury grant, 1839, 1848 (Box 140, Folder 9)
  - Brazoria Co.: Deed of J.D. Rainars to B.F. Mims, 1873 (Box 140, Folder 10)
  - Brazoria Co.: Warranty deed of J.T. Bryan to J.S. Miller, 1877 (Box 140, Folder 11)
  - Brazoria Co.: Deed of Trust from A.E. Stratton to J.O'Connor, 1879 (Box 140, Folder 12)
  - Brazoria Co.: Note of deed conveying land to T.G. Masterson, 1880 (Box 140, Folder 13)
  - Brazoria Co.: Chattel mortgage of cow calf to O. Bess to H. Masterson, 1881 (Box 140, Folder 14)
  - Brazoria Co.: Sheriff's deed of sale of land of F.M. Clary to H. Masterson, 1881 (Box 140, Folder 15)
  - Brazoria Co.: Deed of trust of W. Alston to H. Masterson, 1882 (Box 140, Folder 16)
  - Brazoria Co.: Abstract of Phelps league, 1882 (Box 140, Folder 17)
  - Brazoria Co.: Sheriff's deed to H. Masterson for mare to pay debt, 1883 (Box 140, Folder 18)
  - Brazoria Co.: Deed of Davis Brown Co. to H. Masterson, 1883 (Box 140, Folder 19)
  - Brazoria Co.: Abstract to land, 1883 (Box 140, Folder 20)
  - Brazoria Co.: Assignment of interest in estate of Nancy Randon, 1884 (Box 140, Folder 21)
  - Brazoria Co.: Agreement between H. Masterson and Mrs. H.E. Brooks and Kaufman Range re: trustee's sale, 1885 (Box 140, Folder 22)
  - Brazoria Co.: Mortgage on crops of Mark Eliza White to B.C. Smith, 1888 (Box 140, Folder 23)
  - Brazoria Co.: Warranty deed with vendor's lien of C.R. Cox to D. McDaniel, 1888 (Box 140, Folder 24)
  - Brazoria Co.: Deed of tract of land under dispute in case of G.K. Cessna v. T.W. House J.D. Freeman, 1889 (Box 140, Folder 25)
  - Brazoria Co.: Warranty deed of land to B.C. Smith from J. Saunders, 1889 (Box 140, Folder 26)
  - Brazoria Co.: Settlement of estate of R.J. Smith, 1889-1890 (Box 140, Folder 27)
  - Brazoria Co.: Cancelled note and warranty deed for land in Phelps league, 1889-1893 (Box 140, Folder 28)
  - Brazoria Co.: Notice of trustees sale of cattle of C. Davis, 1891 (Box 140, Folder 29)
  - Brazoria Co.: Sale by Mrs. S.F. Kelly from estate of B.A. Kelly, 1891 (Box 140, Folder 30)
  - Brazoria Co.: Deed of trust between J.H. Shepard H. Stevens/E. Krause, 1891 (Box 140, Folder 31)
  - Brazoria Co.: Writ of attachment for H. Masterson vs. W.L. Sweeny, 1892 (Box 140, Folder 32)
  - Brazoria Co.: Agreement re: purchase of land by H. Masterson C. Fitze, 1892 (Box 140, Folder 33)
  - Brazoria Co.: Notice of trustee sale of stock of S. Dolly, 1892 (Box 140, Folder 34)
  - Brazoria Co.: Trustees sale and deed of trust, Johnson Rawls to Gaines, 1893 (Box 140, Folder 35)
  - Brazoria Co.: Quit claim deed of Charles Suis to H. Masterson, 1894 (Box 140, Folder 36)
  - Brazoria Co.: Report of S. Thompson on abstract of title to Lavaca Navigation Co., 1894 (Box 140, Folder 37)
  - Brazoria Co.: Re: note of Samuel Barber to H. Masterson, 1894-1908 (Box 140, Folder 38)
  - Brazoria Co.: Summons citation in Masterson v. Classen, 1895 (Box 140, Folder 39)
  - Brazoria Co.: Sheriff's bill of sale, J. Murphy to H. Masterson, 1895 (Box 140, Folder 40)
  - Brazoria Co.: Agreement and warranty deed between O.P Martin and L.M. Disney, 1895 (Box 140, Folder 41)
  - Brazoria Co.: Notes with vendor's lien and deed of trust from H. Masterson to T.H. McGuire, 1895-1896 (Box 140, Folder 42)
  - Brazoria Co.: Purchase and rescue of land by H. Masterson, 1895-1904 (Box 140, Folder 43)
  - Brazoria Co.: Note with vendor's lien of A.S. Lacy to D.L. Slataper, 1895-1909 (Box 140, Folder 44)
  - Brazoria Co.: Warranty deed of J.C.F. Amanda Davis to H. Masterson, 1896 (Box 140, Folder 45)
  - Brazoria Co.: Sheriffs deed of sale to H. Masterson in Barron v. Shapard, 1898 (Box 140, Folder 46)
  - Brazoria Co.: Warranty deed of P.B. Compton to H. Masterson, 1899 (Box 140, Folder 47)
  - Brazoria Co.: Deed of contract for Herman Lass to J.L. Hudson, 1901 (Box 140, Folder 48)
  - Brazoria Co.: Purchase of land for Velasco terminal, 1901-1902 (Box 140, Folder 49)
  - Brazoria Co.: Abstract of title for NY TX Oil Co. for mineral rights, 1904 (Box 140, Folder 50)
  - Brazoria Co.: Warranty deed of C.J. Rogers to H. Masterson, 1904 (Box 140, Folder 51)
  - Brazoria Co.: Abstract and certificate of offer of sale for H. Masterson land, 1905 (Box 140, Folder 52)
  - Brazoria Co.: Abstract of William Harris league, 1905 (Box 140, Folder 53)
  - Brazoria Co.: Contract of agreement between H. Masterson and S. TX Development Co., 1905 (Box 140, Folder 54)
  - Brazoria Co.: Corresp. re: title and deed to land bought at executed sale, 1905 (Box 140, Folder 55)
  - Brazoria Co.: H. Masterson to T.W. Smith re: Cornelius Smith tract, 1906 (Box 140, Folder 56)
  - Brazoria Co.: H. Masterson to F.W. Smith re: John Bradley league, 1906 (Box 140, Folder 57)
  - Brazoria Co.: H. Masterson to F.W. Stevens re: "Old Crosby Place," 1906 (Box 140, Folder 58)
  - Brazoria Co.: H. Masterson to F.W. Stevens re: S.M. Williams survey, 1906 (Box 140, Folder 59)
  - Brazoria Co.: H. Masterson to F.W. Stevens re: W. Cummings league, 1906 (Box 140, Folder 60)
  - Brazoria Co.: Notes of J.L. Bullock A.Wild to H. Masterson, 1910-1912 (Box 141, Folder 1)
  - Brazoria Co.: Release of vendor's lien by H. Masterson to R.E. Murrell, 1914 (Box 141, Folder 2)
  - Brazoria Co.: Agreement between J.C. Underwood road commissioners, 1914 (Box 141, Folder 3)
  - Brazoria Co.: Contract for drilling oil between Rubedick D.W. Kitchen T.L. Smith, Jr., 1916 (Box 141, Folder 4)
  - Brazoria Co.: Contract between J.A. MA. Darst heirs re: Damon Mound league, 1917 (Box 141, Folder 5)
  - Cameron Co.: H. Masterson to Spitzer, Rorick Co. re: sale of bonds for Cameron County Irrigation District #1, 1916 (Box 141, Folder 6)
  - Cherokee Co: Warranty deeds of L.A. Youngblood to H.N. Atkinson to H. Masterson, 1907-1909 (Box 141, Folder 7)
  - Colorado Co.: Ratification of sale by C. Stringfellow to J.H. Harris, 1890 (Box 141, Folder 8)
  - Colorado Co.: Abstract of title to Heinsworth property (Box 141, Folder 9)
  - Dimmit Co.: Power of Attorney of J.L. Hudson to H. Masterson, 1917 (Box 141, Folder 10)
  - Dimmit Co.: H. Masterson statement refusing to act as trustee in case of J.L. Hudson, 1917 (Box 141, Folder 11)
  - Ft. Bend Co.: Reaffirmation of deed executed as a minor by R. Pleasants to H. Masterson, 1899 (Box 141, Folder 12)
  - Ft. Bend Co.: Bond indemnifying H.A. Meyer A.E. Pleak against loss by H. Masterson, 1907 (Box 141, Folder 13)
  - Ft. Bend Co.: Affidavit of F. Rose re: possession of property for H. Masterson, 1919 (Box 141, Folder 14)
  - Ft. Bend Co.: Chattel mortgage of W.H. Andrews to J.C. Williams, 1912 (Box 141, Folder 15)
  - Galveston Co.: Sheriff's deed of sale of Opitz property to H. Masterson, 1893 (Box 141, Folder 16)
  - Galveston Co.: Settlement of suit between Luckel Masterson, 1907 (Box 141, Folder 17)
  - Hardin Co.: Contract for representation between R.O. Middlebrook Masterson, Morris Masterson, 1903 (Box 141, Folder 18)
  - Hardin Co.: Certification of ownerships of interests in DeLa Jurza survey, 1904 (Box 141, Folder 19)
  - Hardin Co.: Mortgage of P.H. Nolen in favor of H. Masterson, 1910- 1911 (Box 141, Folder 20)
  - Hardin Co.: Option to lease extended to R.L. Young by H. Masterson, 1914 (Box 141, Folder 21)
  - Hardin Co.: Contract to employ H. Masterson by H.M. Terry for litigation against Sun Pipe Line Co., 1914 (Box 141, Folder 22)
  - Harris Co.: Copy of application for purchase as actual settle of land granted by H.B. T. RR, 1890 (Box 141, Folder 23)
  - Harris Co.: Contract for sale of land by E.E. Davis to R. Robinson, 1898 (Box 141, Folder 24)
  - Harris Co.: Corrected field notes on surveys of Washington Co. RR, 1893 (Box 141, Folder 25)
  - Harris Co.: Corrected field notes on survey of Mrs. S.O. Hawkins, 1894 (Box 141, Folder 26)
  - Harris Co.: Deed of A.Z. Nellie Palmer to C.R. Miller, 1896-1898 (Box 141, Folder 27)
  - Harris Co.: Deed assigning interest in property from H. Masterson to E.E. Davis, 1898 (Box 141, Folder 28)
  - Harris Co.: Copy of deed of J. Hunter to N. Clopper, 1874 (Box 141, Folder 29)
  - Harris Co.: Deed of contract of sale of White Line Moving Storage Co., 1896 (Box 141, Folder 30)
  - Harris Co.: Power of Attorney of L. Jeffers to J.F. Lanier, 1896 (Box 141, Folder 31)
  - Harris Co.: Notes of J. Clems to H. Masterson, 1882 (Box 141, Folder 32)
  - Harris Co.: Transfer of ownership of judgment rendered in District Court in favor of Adoue Lobit to H. Masterson, 1897 (Box 141, Folder 33)
  - Harris Co.: Release by J.O. Furlow of H. Masterson in attorney contract, 1898 (Box 141, Folder 34)
  - Harris Co.: Sale of Mrs. Ida Judd's household items to H. Masterson, 1898 (Box 141, Folder 35)
  - Harris Co.: Sheriff's deed of sale of A.L. Kulp property to H. Masterson, 1899 (Box 141, Folder 36)
  - Harris Co.: Chattel mortgages of J.B. Bleoo to H. Masterson et al., 1912-1913 (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - Harris Co.: Notice of sheriff's sale in J.J. Sweeny v. Thomas Converse, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 2)
  - Harris Co.: Notice of trustee's sale by J.E. Winfree for H. Masterson, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 3)
  - Harris Co.: Receipt and contract of J.P. Jones from H. Masterson, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 4)
  - Harris Co.: Contract for purchase of property of TX Town Lot Improvement Co. to B.D. George, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 5)
  - Harris Co.: Deed of trust of J.J. Atwood to N.T. Masterson, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 6)
  - Harris Co.: Power of Attorney authoring H. Masterson to settle estate of James R. Masterson, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 7)
  - Harris Co.: Power of Attorney replacing H. Masterson for James R. Masterson, deceased, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 8)
  - Harris Co.: Supplement to contact bill of sale between J.C. Underwood and H. Masterson re: Road District #3,1913 (Box 142, Folder 9)
  - Harris Co.: Chattel mortgage on Studebaker from L.W. Swearingen to H. Masterson, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 10)
  - Harris Co.: Notice of sheriff's sale in W.H. Beazley v. E.A. Dewey, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 11)
  - Harris Co.: Bond executed in favor of H. Masterson by San Antonio, Uvalde Gulf Railway Co., 1913 (Box 142, Folder 12)
  - Harris Co.: Affidavit of Mrs. L.L. Pye re: agreement for car sold to W.J. Chambers by F.E. Pye, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 13)
  - Harris Co.: greements between H. Masterson Wm. Moore re: sale of boats, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 14)
  - Harris Co.: Certificate of trustee sale for T. Converse property to H. Masterson, 1913 (Box 142, Folder 15)
  - Harris Co.: Power of Attorney between J.M. Weeden and H. Masterson T.C. Rowe, 1914 (Box 142, Folder 16)